VIRAL PATEL

CREATIVE GRAPHICS, UX UI DESIGNER & 3D VISUALIZER

Mumbai, India

"I Believe That Learning Should Be A Joyful Journey, Not A Destination!..."

A decade of experience with proficiency in CorelDRAW, Adobe Suite, Application UX-UI Designs, Brochure, Catalogues, Web Graphics, & Audio - Video Editing. With an eye for perfection & attention to detail, efficiency, sincerity, hard work and ability to grasp things quickly are my USP. Creating fresh & Unique ideas is my trait so deciding to follow my heart & pursue my passion.

EDUCATION

BCA (Bachelor Of Computer Applications)	2012

Institute Of Management and Engineering (New Delhi)

CERTIFICATIONS

Mobile User Experience (UX) Design		2021
------------------------------------	--	------

Interaction Design Foundation

Fundamentals Of Digital Marketing 2019

Issued Organisation Google [Credential ID: HKU LEF 4MF]

Product Designer — 2019

LinkedIn Learning

SKILLS

Figma	Adobe Premiere Pro	Adobe Illustrator	
Sketch	Adobe XD	Adobe After Effects	
Adobe Photoshop	Invision App		

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

HTML/CSS Website Builder

Autodesk 3Ds Max CorelDRAW X5

FREELANCING

High End Adventourist Logo Design - Mumbai

Designed Website Of Vizkingdom - Rajkot, Gujarat

Barriers International Emailer Designs - Foxley, Malmesbury, UK

CONTACT ME

+91 96999 14386 patelviraln3@gmail.com www.viralpatelstudio.in

FOLLOW ME

LinkedIn.Com/In/Viralpatel16890

Medium.Com/@Viralpatel16890

Twitter.Com/Viralpatel16890

WORK EXPERIENCE

IN-SOLUTIONS GLOBAL LIMITED

Senior Manager - UX Designer

- Apr 2022 to Present
- 1. Worked on the Admin Dashboard UI for clients like J.P. Morgan, ICICI Bank, Axis Bank, PNB, IOB, IDBI, etc.
- 2. Conducting interviews, hiring talent, and expanding the team.
- 3. Analysis, tracking, and management of project progress, as well as delivering on timelines
- 4. Participating in the employee's monthly review and annual performance evaluation
- 5. Leading a team of UI Designers and Frontend Developers to achieve business goals
- 6. Managing Figma organization licenses including Design Systems, Style Guides, Components, and Variants

MOBILE PROGRAMMING LLC

User Experience & User Interface Designer

- Aug 2021 to Apr 2022
- 1. Worked on Insurance Portal Admin Panel Design with Multiple Personas
- 2. Worked on Overseas projects including wireframes, UI mock-ups & prototyping
- 3. Gained Knowledge of Advanced Design System, Style guides, Components & Variants
- 4. Designed AR and VR related prototypes for immersive experience

TEJORA TECHNOLOGIES PVT. LTD.

Software Engineer - UX/UI Designer

— Jan 2021 to Jun 2021

- 1. Designed UX UI for SaffronPay products to be used by the IndusInd bank & ICICI Bank
- 2. Enhanced the complete responsive website interface in liaison with development team
- 3. Designed Mailers & Landing pages for bulk sending bulk emails using Sugar Market & Mailchimp
- 4. Was Involved in team brainstorming for Social media posts & HR Job postings

JUST DIAL PVT. LTD.

Creative Graphics, UI/UX Designer & Audio - Video Editor

Oct 2018 to Jan 2021

- 1. Designed Mobile UI of the Learning Centre in liaison with Learning and Development Team
- 2. Created & edited Sales training video tutorials
- 3. Lead and manage creative projects for social media
- 4. Supportive team leader, mentor to designers to enable the best work within deadlines

GANDHI AUTOMATIONS PVT. LTD.

Creative Graphics Designer, 3D Visual Animator + VFX Editor

Nov 2017 to Oct 2018

- 1. Creatively enhancing Social Media profiles with the goal to increase organisation & event awareness
- 2. Acquired experience in dealing & coordinating with clients, vendors to finalise the output
- 3. Designed the panels of 3D stalls to be exhibited in Germany & other foreign countries
- 4. Conceptualised & created product promotional video for marketing requirements

RESTAR 3P CONSULTANTS LLP.

Creative Graphics Designer, Animator, Audio-Video Editor

Sep 2015 to Nov 2017

- 1. Undertook design concept creation, planning, & execution
- 2. Cracked briefs for branding assignments & transformed subject matter to concrete designs
- 3. Worked extensively across various media like Brochures, Standees, & Visual Aids
- 4. Conceptualised, designed & handled social media platforms to increase growth & audience engagement

GIANT WHEEL - THE ANIMATION RIDE

Sr. Faculty - Graphics Designer, 3D Animation & VFX

Jan 2015 to Sep 2015

ARIHANT ACADEMY - COMMERCE SECTION

I.T - Information Technology Trainer

- Oct 2012 to Mar 2015

RAJ SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY [INDIA] PVT. LTD.

Faculty - Graphics, Web Designing, 2D-3D Animation & VFX

Jul 2012 to Jan 2015